The red light's on.
T-that means
we're ready, yeah?
'Yes.'
Would you,
uh, tell us why and how
a psychic
becomes a CBI agent?
I'm not a psychic.
No such things as psychics.
And he's not a CBI agent.
He's a consultant.
Big difference.
"No such thing as psychics."
Uh, care to elaborate?
Uh, no, not particularly.
Um...you know what,
this-this is not..
This is not a good idea,
I don't think..
Um, not a good idea.
[clears throat]
'Okay.'
'Um, maybe we'll-we'll'
'come back to that later.'
'Uh, how do your
cases usually start?'
Uh, a case begins with
us getting a phone call
from the AG's office
to lead an investigation.
In the St. Clare homicide
the local DA wanted us on it
because there were
political issues involved.
And how did
the local cops feel
about your-your team
coming in?
We get along extremely well
with our local partners
in law enforcement, yes.
My people can handle this,
no problem.
California Bureau of
Interference is what you are.
Interference?
- That's witty.
- Stay out of this.
I'm sure your people are
competent, Chief Donner.
We're simply following
the AG's orders.
Screw the AG.
This case is going
to be in the news
and you people are
spotlight hogs.
- That's all.
- I assure you, chief--
Don't waste your time,
his anger runs
deeper than you can reach.
Seriously,
don't start trouble here.
It's the last
thing we need.
The victim is
Martha St. Clare, 34.
Media relations coordinator
'for the mayor of this town.'
Mayor was here
to break ground
on a new development.
Dug up her PR flack instead.
Ouch.
Yeah, victim was stabbed
twice in the chest
but there's
no blood here.
Killed elsewhere.
Home.
Her nails are done.
Her hair's done.
This woman doesn't
wear sweatpants anywhere
but at home.
Cho, have Van Pelt
check it out.
Yeah.
The killer wanted
the body to be discovered here
under the glare
of the cameras.
And likely came here
to watch the fuss.
Likely.
Maybe the camera crews
caught something.
We'll need to have
them look into it.
[sniffing]
There's bruises on her arms.
Looks like something
was ripped off her neck
during the struggle.
Is he sniffing her?
Yes.
You pay him to sniff people?
Apparently.
She's been smoking.
The nicotine
patch on her arm
says she
was trying to quit.
So under
stress of late.
Well, case closed.
Stress got a knife
and stabbed her to death.
He's on a roll.
You're on a roll.
[sniffs]
Cheap soap.
Unironed shirt.
Stomach pains.
Recent loss of weight.
I'm gonna
take a wild guess here.
You're angry
and unhappy
'cause you're
living in a motel
because your wife
found out about the woman
you're having
an affair with
that you don't
even care for.
You're a seething mass
of self-loathing
and understandably so.
You son of a bitch!
Donner,
my apologies.
He was completely
out of line.
Let-let's just get
back to the body. Sir?
[theme music]
We've closed more cases
than any other unit in the CBI.
But we don't
keep score that way.
It's not a contest.
And you-you also...lead
in the number of complaints
'and lawsuits filed.'
Okay, hold it.
I thought we had an agreement.
Brenda, a word.
Jane's right.
This isn't a good idea.
I thought this was supposed
to be positive coverage.
It is! It will be.
If we're open
and honest about the issues
the positivity follows.
That's PR 101.
We're trying to solve
a woman's murder here, Brenda.
We don't have time
to waste on PR.
Teresa, you know that we have
been crucified by the media
ever since Bosco
and his team were killed
'here in our own house.'
'When KTQZ asked me'
for access yesterday
I jumped at it.
And the deputy AG concurred.
Who is this guy anyway?
Totally legit,
TV investigative reporter
'Mike Brewster.'
He has been covering
the central valley for years.
We need this.
Teresa. Please.
Work with us.
He stays out of my way.
He can film in the office
and in the bullpen
but not out in the field.
Thank you.
Seriously, thank you.
You won't be sorry,
and it's a two-way street.
Agent Lisbon, if there's
anything I can do for you.
There is one thing.
[Brewster]
Okay, so this is
the footage Steve and I
grabbed of the groundbreaking.
That's the mayor.
'Melba, Walker, Shannon.'
She plays up the folksy image
but she'd be tough as nails,
if she needs to be.
Nice shoes.
Chip?
No, thanks. Who's the rich guy
next to the mayor?
'Oh, that's Heaton Krupp.'
He's the private
developer on the project.
Off the record, a prize jerk.
- Who are those people?
- 'Tree huggers.'
'The project's going up on the
edge of some reclaimed land.'
You mean protected wildlands.
You say "potato."
You have any other
footage of the crowds?
Not really.
Other networks might.
But gaining access
can be tricky.
It'd be good to get
a different perspective.
Cho, see if you can
get the footage.
You got it.
'Alright,
that's Wilson Fonteneau.'
The mayor's flunky.
And here comes the money shot.
Oh.
[button clicks]
These are from
the victim's home.
Besides the signs
of a scuffle
the only thing that
seemed to be missing
was the victim's laptop.
The murderer
probably took it.
Check out this necklace.
From the photos, it looks
like she wore it a lot.
You think it could have
made the mark on her neck?
Could be, when you
go to the apartment
do a targeted search.
The necklace is long gone.
My guess, killer
made a souvenir of it.
- Go.
- Okay.
Where we going?
Mayor's office.
I don't have any problem
being in charge, no.
I mean, maybe,
at first for a while
as a woman,
it was a challenge.
But...the demands
of the job take over. Yeah.
[Brewster]
'Tell me about your weekends.'
You wanna know
what I do on my weekends?
'Yeah.'
Why do you want to know that?
I mean, I have
no problem having a life.
If that's what you mean.
I don't know why anybody
would say otherwise.
If they do...say otherwise.
Um, I'm...I'm sorry.
What were we talking about?
[theme music]
Sorry for the delay.
The mayor's just
finishing up another meeting.
It's been
a crazy day around here.
Can I help you?
Oh, no, I'm fine. Thanks.
[Lisbon]
'Mr. Fonteneau,
did you work closely'
'with Martha St. Clare?'
For 16 months.
Martha hired me,
actually.
We noticed in a lot
of recent photographs
that she had
a-a necklace on
with a beautiful stone.
Yes, a topaz, I think.
It was her birthstone.
She got it
Christmas of last year
and never took it off.
Do you know
who gave it to her?
- No.
- She had a lot of meetings.
Even on weekends.
Business interests,
community groups, book club.
Tomorrow is a big day.
She has a star and three
exclamation marks at eleven.
Yes.
Uh, she scheduled
a briefing
with the city council.
On what subject?
I don't know,
to be honest.
The mayor will know.
Was she dating anyone?
A social life? Martha?
No, she had a cat.
Ah. Yes.
But it died.
Right.
Excuse me.
Are you the CBI agents?
Mayor, thank you
for seeing us.
Happy to help,
and please call me Melba.
Like the toast?
Just like.
This way.
Can you tell us about
your construction project
that you were
opening yesterday?
It's the Granton Complex.
Yes, we areveryproud of it.
'It's office and retail space'
'plus housing, all built'
with the latest
green technology.
And what was Martha's
involvement in the project?
None, really, she..
...she was my..
...media liaison.
She was not engaged
in policy issues.
Then what
was she gonna talk
about at city council tomorrow?
Oh, a press junket.
It was river rafting,
I believe.
'Chief Donner says your office'
has received several threats
from environmental activists.
Activists?
No, they're terrorists.
They burned down vacation
condos up on the mountain.
'They destroyed luxury car
lots just one town over.'
They're led by a madman,
and he calls himself Jasper.
- Uh..
- Excuse me.
Wilson, anything else can wait.
- The threats?
- 'Yes.'
'Um..'
The Granton development
is an abomination.
'A hundred acres
of pristine wildlands razed.'
'An entire
ecosystem endangered.'
It must stop.
It will stop, no matter
what needs to be done.
My name is Jasper..
...and I am legion.
[chuckling]
Come on.
"I am legion."
That's just silly.
- Silly?
- Yeah.
He murdered Martha.
Well, you assume.
Yes, I do.
The body was buried
at the site, for God's sake.
And that is
a clear message.
Isn't it?
Melba..
...why would
he kill Martha..
...and not kill you?
It'd be a bigger
publicity coup.
Excuse me?
What Mr. Jane
is trying to ask
is whether there was
somebody with a more
direct personal
grudge against Martha.
- Mm.
- Yeah.
No.
She was a lovely..
...was a lovely person.
Oh, then why did you
dislike her so much?
I didn't dislike Martha.
Why would I employ
someone that...I don't like?
Well, that's
a very good question.
When you said it,
your jaw tensed
and your eyes went
empty like a cobra.
Wilson!
I'm not saying you killed her,
I'm just saying
that you're relieved
that she's dead.
These people
will be leaving now.
I like the way
you say that.
Melba like the toast,
so tough and commanding.
Now, let me tell you something.
We are state
law enforcement
and we leave
when we want to leave.
Thank you for your time.
She wants to leave.
See you.
You blew my cool.
I swear, sometimes
I think you need medication.
It's like you've got
ADD or something.
Well, "A,"
I'm not so sure that
ADD even exists
and "B," I was winding
her up for a reason.
- Which is?
- A diversion.
The message the aide
brought in made her nervous.
- So I took it.
- You're stealing now?
Well, let's just
call it purloining.
What does it say?
It says,
"Your 3 o'clock meeting
has now
been moved to 3:15."
I'm just kidding.
It says,
"911. Call now.
"Urgent. About Martha.
From Heaton Krupp."
The developer
of the Granton Project.
Oh, yeah.
[Brewster]
'Do you enjoy police work?'
Mm..
'Patrick?'
Uh, yeah, I'm thinking.
Uh..
Yes and no.
Uh, yeah, sometimes.
Sometimes not.
Forget it, Steve.
Why do you so dislike
being filmed?
Uh..
'Cause you're
stealing my soul.
So I called the mayor.
So what?
I'm building a $20 million
complex in her town.
I call her a lot.
About Ms. St. Clare?
About when I can start
construction again.
This is costing me hundreds
of thousands of dollars.
It cost
Ms. St. Clare a lot more.
And I'm sorry about that.
I am. But there's nothing
I can do about it.
Martha would have
wanted us to go on.
You knew her
well enough to know that?
You're right.
I'm being pious.
Maybe Martha would
have said, "Screw it."
I knew her not at all
outside of business.
Really? 'Cause we just got
her cellphone records
and you called her
ten times yesterday.
Wanna tell us what you wanted to
talk about so urgently?
Seems I should get my lawyer.
Have him sit in with us.
Sure. That's your right.
Tell him
to bring all your
permits for
the Granton Project.
- My permits? Why?
- Why not?
And we should make sure this
stays an active crime scene.
Keep everyone out
until the case is solved.
It could take weeks.
See..
We were talking
about money, okay?
Ten million dollars
of public funds
was to be released
when we broke ground.
Then I heard rumors
that St. Clare
was planning to tell the city
council to withhold them.
- Why?
- I don't know!
I mean, that's what
I was trying to find out.
But St. Clare
was killed before
she could talk
to the city council.
Yes, but--
So the $10 million will
come to you after all.
What are you trying to
lay this on me?
Because you're messing
with the wrong guy, officer!
We're not officers.
We're agents.
That's quite
a temper you got there.
[glass shatters]
Look out!
Ah! My leg!
- Grab him.
- Get down!
Get on the floor!
[shouting]
Put it out!
Wayne, put it out.
Get the door!
Go, go, go, go!
- Hang on!
- I got the door!
[grunting]
- Ah!
- You're fine.
It's jammed!
I got you.
[glass shatters]
[coughs]
[grunting]
[all coughing]
This was done
by someone who knew
what he or she was doing.
[coughing]
Crackpot Jasper.
He's a terrorist
and you ain't doing jack
to catch him, chief.
I'm in charge of the town
of Salter, Mr. Krupp.
Not the outlying areas.
Jasper's never
launched an attack here
in town before.
Until now.
Hey! Check this out.
Apparently, this is
the same tag that Jasper
used in the attack
on the condos.
This good, sir?
[Brewster]
'It's great.'
Uh, I've been
in fires before.
I worked with the,
uh, Arson Squad in San Diego
for a couple years, so..
...I'm not unfamiliar
with the issues.
It's never pleasant, though.
Um...I mean, when you're,
when you're in it
it's-there's no
time to think.
But...but afterwards, well..
...yeah.
It can make you think.
There was a..
There was a moment
there, where, uh..
[rattling]
Yeah, makes you think.
It's a gift, isn't it?
Life.
You should be
grateful for it.
Make the most of it.
We have to catch this guy
before he kills someone else.
He hasn't killed anyone yet.
- Not Martha St. Clare?
- Nah.
Martha St. Clare was about
to stall the development.
That exactly what Jasper
wants. So why kill her?
[Lisbon]
'Maybe he didn't
know Martha's intentions.'
But the mayor must have known.
Let's go see her.
Yeah. You guys look
into this Jasper character.
Don't bother.
He's a red herring.
What does that mean,
anyway, a red herring?
A red herring
is what you look into
regardless
of what Jane tells you.
Anything on
the networks' footage?
They've been
throwing up hurdles.
Something about
first amendment issues.
Get the footage. I'm tired
of hearing their excuses.
We ID somebody in the crowd,
maybe we get lucky.
Yes, boss.
Why am I a detective?
Why are you a reporter?
[Brewster]
'What?'
Why are you making
this documentary?
'It's a fresh perspective
on law enforcement.'
No, I mean,
what's in it for you?
'Well, uh,
scoring this exclusive'
'is a good way
to get noticed.'
So you're ambitious.
How long you been
doing the news here?
- 'About eight years.'
- Anchor?
'Mostly fieldwork.'
So you're ambitious,
but you haven't gotten very far.
I, uh, I guess
that's about it, yeah.
'Uh, you don't like'
being asked
questions, do you?
The team as a whole
seems to have
a problem with that.
Is that a question?
Mike, if I can
interrupt here?
- Yeah.
- We're clear.
Uh, there's coffee
in the kitchen, John.
I'm so sorry.
- Agent Cho?
- Yeah?
It is the specific
request of the deputy AG
that your unit cooperate
fully with the media.
What's your point?
[coughs]
[Rigsby clears throat]
Oh.
Mayor Shannon,
we need to talk.
Of course. I have a meeting.
Please make it fast.
Sure, how big
was your bribe
from Heaton Krupp?
That is an outrageous slander.
You sold your approval
of the Granton Project.
Martha found out,
she was gonna reveal it
at the city
council meeting
which you said
was gonna be
about river rafting,
of all things.
River rafting,
from where did you pull that?
You better have
really good personal lawyers.
If you pursue this
absurd line of harassment
I will hang you
by your heels.
Did you get
a slice, too?
Or are you
strictly wage labor?
Your superiors will hear
from our lawyers.
Oh, don't bother
with lawyers.
It's such a waste
of taxpayer dollars.
Just confess.
You'll feel a lot better.
In actuality, you have no proof
of this so-called bribery.
Uh, none at all.
Are all CBI agents
this incompetent?
Have you even bothered to check
her lover as a suspect?
First you say it was Jasper.
Now it's the lover that did it.
- You gonna make up your mind?
- What lover?
We understood
she had no social life.
I didn't know she did.
Oh, well, she did, and competent
police would have known that.
Why didn't you tell us
this earlier?
Why don't I just do your job
foryou? How would that be?
Oh, just please arrest her
or something.
Nothing to hold her on.
Eh.
I'm the rookie on the team.
Been here...18 months now.
Um, it's hard work
but this has been my dream
ever since I was a kid.
To be a detective.
'And what's been
the most surprising thing'
'you've learned
about this job you do?'
I've..
...learned a lot about myself.
As well as, about other people.
Stuff...I wish
I didn't know sometimes.
'Stuff like..'
Why people do bad things
to one another.
It's mainly because of secrets.
Trying to hide the truth
chips away at your spirit.
Secrets ruin relationships.
We finally got the footage from
every news station
covering
the groundbreaking ceremony.
Apparently, threats work.
These are two separate
vantage points of the mayor
and these are feeds
of the crowd. There, that guy.
[Lisbon]
'Can you narrow it down for us?
There's, like, 50 guys there.'
The guy in the crowd there after
the mayor digs up the victim.
He certainly doesn't
look like he fits in.
"J."
That's bold.
- A Jasper acolyte.
- Or the man himself.
Get with the local PD.
See if they can identify him.
- 'What is it?'
- Nothing. Just hungry.
So we went back
to St. Clare's apartment
went through her closet
and realized
that some of her work shirts--
- Button on the right.
- Yeah, and not her size.
So the mayor was right.
She did have a lover.
Of course she had a lover.
That necklace she always wore
was obviously a romantic gift.
She'd never spend
that kind of money on herself.
Now you say so.
Very wise in hindsight.
Well, I thought
it went without saying.
It's horribly obvious when
people are in a relationship
impossible to hide,
try though they might.
She was a very attractive woman.
I would not be surprised
if she had two lovers.
There is nothing here.
I'm gonna go out for lunch.
Turn that thing off, or I will
shove it down your throat.
Let's take a walk,
shall we? Come on.
I know it hasn't been
the most pleasant experience
having a camera crew here.
But you gotta cooperate.
Deputy AG's orders.
Yeah.
So what's the deal?
I would think out of everybody
you'd be the most comfortable
with the cameras.
Last time I was
in front of a camera
things, uh,
didn't turn out so well.
Oh, God, Jane, I'm sorry.
You don't need to be sorry.
And you're right.
There's no reason not to be
civil. I'm going to apologize.
Hey, I'm sorry.
We didn't mean to be intrusive.
No, I-I shouldn't
have snapped at you.
I'm sorry. I just...I don't
like feeling spied on.
It's my own little neurosis.
You're just doing
your job, right?
Right.
Well, let me buy you a taco.
- Sure.
- I know you're in.
- I am kind of hungry.
- Well, that's the spirit.
I know the perfect place.
Vamonos.
Muchas gracias.
- Mike.
- Thank you.
Steve. So tell me about
news gathering.
Out of my way!
Whoa! Whoa!
[crowd screaming]
Did you get that?
Did you get it?
Keep moving.
Let's go.
I don't know where we're going,
but I hope there's a bathroom.
I am busting.
Oh.
[chatter]
Definitely Jasper.
The description of the van
matches one seen
near the condo fire
and the luxury car lot
Jasper destroyed.
How long has Chief Donner
had this information?
Contact the local
and the county PD.
On it.
We got a hit on
the Jasper associate
at the groundbreaking ceremony.
Local activists
draw the line at kidnapping.
- They gave this guy up fast.
- Bart Henrik.
On his blog, he calls himself
a green warrior.
He's been arrested several times
for inciting a riot
public disorder and vandalism.
- Go find him. Take Rigsby.
- You got it.
Watch your step.
I can see you mean business.
Uh, there's no need
for firearms.
I'm not Harry Houdini.
Quiet.
Thank you.
So you're Jasper.
Well, I'm honored.
Please don't say
you kidnapped me for ransom
because I-I doubt you'll get
$50, let alone save the whales.
No ransom. In actuality,
just a simple message.
I did not kill
Martha St. Clare
and I didn't throw that
firebomb in Krupp's office.
Now, you, you are gonna
tell that to the police
and to the media.
So you kidnapped me
to proclaim your innocence.
Have you ever heard
of a phone?
Oh, yeah. I see.
If you kidnap me
and I pass on the message
then you get a blast of
that publicity that you love.
If I am branded a killer
everything I have fought
for is discredited.
People support me because I have
respect for all living things.
Yes, but it's
a good rule of thumb
to avoid doing things
that require you to wear a mask.
And you're such a
handsome fellow, too.
How'd you know
I'm handsome?
Well, I was just speaking
figuratively.
No, you weren't.
- You know who I am.
- No, I have no idea.
Leave us
and don't come back.
'No, he doesn't have
to go anywhere.'
I-I-I.. Will you listen to me?
I have no idea.
You could be Elvis Presley,
for all I know.
- 'How did you know?'
- I don't know.
How did you..
Please don't do that.
How did you know?
Well, what's not to know?
Your height,
your body language.
Your syntax.
You said "in actuality."
I mean, who-who says
"in actuality?"
Yes.
Yeah.
Very clever.
So now we have a problem.
Get that thing out of my face!
Jasper kidnapped our colleague.
- Where are they?
- Jasper who?
Did you know you can
get more time
for kidnapping
than murder?
That's crazy, right?
And being an accessory
after the fact
makes you just as guilty
as Jasper.
Man, Jasper's avenging
Mother Earth. That's all.
You know him well enough
to be sure of his motives.
Yes.
You know him so well you can
tell us where he might be.
Even if I knew,
which I don't
I would never betray Jasper.
- Never is a big word.
- Try me.
What would Jane want us
to do in this situation, Cho?
With his life in jeopardy?
You know what
he'd want us to do.
Yep. Okay.
I guess we have to go.
There.
We should call an ambulance.
It's procedure.
Sure. They can set it fast
and we can get
straight back to questioning.
Wait. Set what?
[clanks]
Your arm, you broke it,
slipped on the stairs.
Yeah, you should
be more careful, Henrik.
Hey. Hey, a bunch of people
saw me come in here, fine.
A bunch of cops,
and I'm one of them.
I saw you fall.
And every cop in this building
will say exactly the same.
[thud]
A cabin in the Sierra Foothills.
Ten miles northeast of Salter.
Nice work.
What to do?
If I let you go now,
you'll rat me out.
- If I may make a suggestion?
- No, you may not.
Please, Wilson,
I can help.
I cannot go to prison.
I need to finish my work.
Don't you see?
I do, I see, your work
is very important.
But what I don't
understand though
is why you were working
in the mayor's office.
Where better
to study the enemy
than from within
their very camp?
Did you know that the mayor
was taking bribes
from the developer Krupp?
Of course.
Who do you think
put Martha onto it?
Ah. You told her.
But why not expose the mayor
yourself or do it as Jasper?
They would know that Jasper
was inside the mayor's office.
They would soon suspect me.
I work in the shadows,
that's why I am still here.
Still fighting.
I understand.
Let me help you.
Don't try to play me.
Don't go saying you won't tell
on me if I set you free
because I know you will.
Wilson, I am not trying
to play you.
I will not play you.
I understand and respect
your intelligence.
Have a seat.
Just take a moment.
Wilson, look at me.
I can help you.
How?
Look at me.
You can see that
I'm telling the truth.
I want what you want.
Peace and harmony.
'Peace..'
...quiet.
It's easy.
You can have it.
'If you want it,
you can have it.'
So peaceful.
'This is Chief Donner of
the Salter Police Department!'
'You're completely surrounded.
Come out with your hands up!'
Stay cool.
Just stay cool.
Go.
- Clear!
There's a trap door.
- I got him.
- Lisbon?
- Jane.
- Wow, I'm impressed.
How the hell did you
find me out here?
Right, because
we're lost without you?
I wouldn't say that,
but I'm still impressed.
- Wait. D-Don't move.
- Oh.
They could have
booby-trapped the place.
We'll have the bomb squad
take a look at you.
What? Oh, you're kidding.
You're kidding.
I'm-I'm thankful and all that
'but just get me out of here'
'and I'll tell you the story.'
- What story?
- Ahh.
- So we know who Jasper is.
- Fonteneau.
No trace of him. Slipped right
through the locals' hands.
He's one guy,
for crying out loud.
He obviously knows
those woods a lot better.
Jane, enough recovery time.
Tell us about Fonteneau.
What'd he say?
Well, he sprouted
a lot of nonsense, denial.
Truth is, he took the job
in the mayor's office
to plan targeted attacks
on new developments around town.
He and St. Clare became lovers.
Secret boyfriend.
But when St. Clare found out
about Fonteneau's
secret life as Jasper
he killed her for it,
to keep her quiet.
I'll check on the warrant
for Fonteneau's place.
Get everybody briefed,
suited up and ready to roll.
Oh, look for
St. Clare's necklace.
It was a gift from Fonteneau.
[Patrick]
'My guess, he took it
when he killed her. We need it.'
You guys sit on the location
until the warrant comes in.
Chief Donner?
Yeah, i-it's Lisbon.
Oh, I need some Aspirin.
[Lisbon]
'Yeah.'
Yeah, I-I just wanted..
could you hold on, chief?
Look, that's enough, guys.
We're done filming.
You know, catching
the bad guy would be
a great end of the show, make
you guys look like superstars.
Well, it'd certainly make
the deputy AG very happy.
True.
Alright,
you can film the bust
but you have to do
exactly what I say.
Deal.
Meet me at Fonteneau's
at 06:00 hours.
- Yes, ma'am.
- Hey, chief.
We're gonna need assistance
from your entry team again.
[sighs]
What now?
We set a perimeter
and wait for the warrant.
Yeah, there's a lot
of this kind of stuff.
Not too many car chases.
Maybe we could, uh, ask a few
questions while we're waiting?
Uh..
Sure. If you must.
[clears throat]
Um, how did you come
to work with the CBI?
You know how.
Yes, but I-I need you
to say it to the camera.
Yeah, yeah,
I-I see. I got it.
[sighs]
Um..
Well, I came
to work with the CBI
after my wife and child
were murdered.
Have you ever
experienced loss like that?
A loss of love?
There's nothing more important
than love, is there?
Well, we're talking about you.
Yeah.
It can be very hard
when love goes away.
It's like a...a betrayal.
Almost like a
violent act, right?
- Right?
- I guess.
Um, why don't-why don't
we go back to, um--
When you give someone your heart
and they throw it aside
it's natural to be angry.
Especially when you've come
to rely on 'em.
When your career
is tied to theirs.
I don't know
what you're..
Why don't you show us
what you got in your pockets?
- What?
- You heard me.
- No.
- Why not?
Because you don't
have the right.
Okay.
Okay. I'll tell you
what you have in your pocket
and you tell me if I'm right.
In your pocket, you have
a blue topaz necklace
that you once gave
to Martha St. Clare
when you were lovers.
You took that necklace back
after you killed her.
You were gonna plant it
in Fonteneau's house.
Prompted by
my cunningly brilliant ruse.
Aha.
Aha. That's it.
I don't know
how that got in there.
Oh, please. Don't be so silly.
Arrest him, Cho.
Get on your knees.
Put your hands on your head.
Now!
Get up.
That's for you.
And this..
...is for me.
Here it comes.
Bang. There.
You looked away.
Martha St. Clare's body
hasn't been revealed
and you looked away, because you
knew what was gonna happen
because you buried that body
at that building site
and you firebombed the trailer
to try and frame Jasper.
You're too clever, Mike,
you're just too clever.
Nah. You spout
a lot of theory
but no legal proof.
You want legal proof?
The lab reports came back.
They found traces of Martha's
blood in the trunk of your car.
[Lisbon]
'Do you want to tell us
what happened?'
Rumors said
the mayor was dirty
but there was no proof.
I knew something was up.
But...no matter
how much I pushed her
Martha wouldn't
say anything. Nothing.
And last night..
I was going through
her computers.
Checking on some stuff,
you know?
I found this speech
she was preparing to give
exposing the mayor,
as corrupt.
With proof.
Facts and figures,
the whole deal.
And she kept it from me
the whole time.
This is a story
that could've made my career.
'I have been waiting
for a story like this'
'my whole life.'
And she's mad 'cause
I'm on her computer.Hello.
So she..
She said, uh, she couldn't trust
me anymore and that it was over.
The argument escalated
and, uh, I took
my necklace back.
And then she starts
taunting me.
Implying that
I don't have what it takes
to be in the big leagues
anyway.
Saying I'm a loser.
She's had enough?
She's had enough? She has?
No, no, no, no.
I've had enough. Me!
Well..
We'll take that
as a confession.
In a stunning revelation,
Mayor Melba Walker Shannon
'has been arrested by the DA
for corruption charges'
stemming from the Granton
at Salter development.
The accuser is her
closest aide, Wilson Fonteneau
'who agreed to testify
against the mayor'
in exchange for leniency
regarding his activities
as eco-terrorist Jasper.
'This only
the latest development'
in a bizarre story
of murder and greed
that has captivated
the Central Valley.
Hey. I was enjoying that.
Ugh. I hate how they
over-dramatize everything.
Yeah, I hate that.
Captivated the Central Valley.
- Give me a break.
- Doughnuts.
Ladies first.
So, uh, guys?
Uh, I have something to say.
Wehave something to say.
Uh, life's too short
for dishonesty.
Van Pelt..
Grace and I are lovers.
No, you're not.
- Um, yes, we are.
- No, you are not lovers.
Uh, but we are, though.
No, you're not.
Because a sexual relationship
between two fellow
bureau employees
is strictly against the rules.
Which is why
we kept it a secret.
But we don't want
to live a lie anymore.
Come what may.
[chuckles]
Well, it's a big secret.
Well kept.
Maybe you knew,
but nobody else did.
I knew.
Half the building knows.
- They do not.
- 'Yes they do.'
The only person that didn't know
is glaring at you right now.
And now I have
to do something about it.
- What are you gonna do?
- Yeah, whatareyou gonna do?
I'm thinking.
'Go.'
[male narrator]
Stay tuned for scenes
from our next episode.
[theme music]